Derek Quach

Seattle, WA

. 206-372-4149 | ■ derek.quach15@gmail.com | 🖸 dnqUW | 🛅 derek-quach-4b69a51aa/ | Portfolio

Personal Profile

Software engineer of 1 professional year & 4 collegiate years, Technical writer with 1.5 years, IT tech of 2 years, and 5+ years writing for target audiences. English BA & Bio AA. Excellent: project management, programming, SEO/keyword research, verbal and writing skills. Has experience and familar with SSO, SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle), REST API, JSON. Works well with developers, SMEs, software, and SSO in sprints.

Skills

Programming Java, SQL, Markdown, HTML, Oxygen XML, CSS, JScript, Git, GitHub (Click here for Certifications)

Unit tests, functional testing, system performance testing, load testing, Technical Writing, Concise documentation, APIs, Java, SQL,

Technical HTML, JScript, Oxygen XML, Madcap Flare, Confluence, MS Suite, Adobe suite, Yoast SEO, Microsoft 365, CRM, DaVinci Resolve,

Data structures, Algorithms, Figma

Soft Skills Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Friendly, Engaging Presentation.

Work Experience _____

Revature Reston, VA

Bootcamp Software Engineer May 2023 - Sept 2023

• Aced all 93 (combined) Java and SQL coding labs, challenges, and mini-projects

- 100% completion & score on all assignments and labs. SQL queries, Big O, data structures, algorithms.
- Developed social media API application and corresponding technical documentation

Upwork Seattle, WA

Technical Writer Sept 2023 - Present

- Documented, maintained, and released a high-level 54-page document meant to instruct general audiences.
- Maintained and optimized internal documentation to increase general audience readability by 20%.
- Employed Google Docs, Confluence and to reach 26 domain authority and to increase SEO score by 23%.

humanID Cambridge, MA

Technical Writing Team Lead 2022 - 2023

- · Maintained all tech writing standard operating procedures, tutorials, training manuals, and field documentation of our SaaS login
- Expanded blog's article count for technical audiences by 10% and optimized SEO score and web traffic by 15%
- Instructed and delegated over 50 technical writing tasks and tracked three onboarding processes single-handedly

humanID Cambridge, MA

Technical Writing Intern 2022 - 2023

- 23% augmentation rate domain authority. Suitability for general audience average score from 80% to 90%
- · Utilized graphics to supplement clear and concise documentation. Surpassed expected quantity of deliverables
- Slashed documentation delivery time by 25% while working with software engineers & SME team

Education

University of Washington Tacoma, WA

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

University of Washington Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Arts: English

Highline College Des Moines, WA

Associate of Science: Biology

Projects_____

Hex to Decimal to Binary Calculator

Tacoma, WA

University of Washington

2022

- Developed entirely by self
- Developed project that allowed operations to hex, decimal, and binary characters
- Scored 4.0 in course
- Technical Skills: Binary, Hex, Decimal characters, Java.

August 28, 2024